Howdy there!
Today I am going to explain a very simple and very simple thing
basic, but that we all should know
when you want to play disc golf.
What kind of discs there are.
There are 4 types of discs.
Basically.
There's the putters, there's the midranges,
there are the fairway drivers and there are the distance drivers.
How are the four discs different from each other?
what they're used for is pretty important.
The difference between the discs is, basically,
the width of the disc and the aerodynamics it has.
I mean, how well the disc cuts off the air.
The more the disc cuts the air, the farther it goes.
To begin with, the shortest distance
they're called putters.
As you can see here, the putter has a
pretty wide profile.
Moving on, there's the midranges.
As you can see here, the profile is a little bit
more aerodynamic.
Following we have a fairway driver and by
last a distance driver.
We can then compare a midrange with
a putter.
As you can see, the putter, which is the orange,
has a much wider profile.
The difference between a
and a fairway driver can also be appreciated
in the profile.
And between a fairway driver and a distance driver
you can see that the distance driver, which is
yellow, it's a lot thinner.
Having different types of discs allows us to
adjust the distance as well as the accuracy.
The more aerodynamic the disc, the less
precision we're going to have.
Why is that?
That's because it's going to be very affected by the wind.
With a midrange we'll have a little
more precision and with a putter a lot
more precision.
Of course we're talking every time about
shorter shots in distance.
The putter also, apart from being used to make the
latest approaches, it is used to make
the last shot.
That's why we say that the putter is the most accurate,
because it's the one who's going to give you
that ability to aim and put it in.
The last thing I want to tell you is how
the professionals use the discs and how are used by
the ones that are a little more amateur.
Professionals usually throw a putter
up to a distance of about 80 to 100m
(if you're not Simon Lizotte in W.A.C.O., who threw out
a putter, a P2, which is what I have in the
hand right now, 150m ¡Beast!).
Then you have the midrange between 80 and 100m.
The fairway driver between 90 and 110.
And from 110-120m they are already pulling a distance
driver.
Why do they do that?
Because the slower the disc, as
I said earlier, the more precision you're going to have.
And the amateurs, we don't have that distance,
Well, at least I, I throw a putter up to
60-70 meters.
It's the distance where I feel comfortable throwing it.
I say, "okay, I'm pretty accurate".
Then I'm going to use a midrange
up to about 80 meters, a fairway driver up to
about 90-95m and a distance driver from
95-100 meters.
My current maximum distance, at the time of
recording this is 120m, so let's not exaggerate
a lot, I don't shoot that far, but well, that
is more or less what I use and how
I use it.
Well, thank you so much for watching the video.
The truth is that we, Manolo and I are not
the best, but we're trying to make everything that is
possible to improve every day and also
take a little bit of the information
that we collect in different places, both in
English as well as German and the people who
teaches stuff to us to put it in Spanish for any
person who wants to learn,
to have the opportunity of doing so.
And of course, if you liked it,
hit the like button, subscribe and share it
it helps a lot.
And if you have any questions, please write to us.
You can write to us right here in the chat,
you can leave us a comment, you can me
find us in instagram, facebook, twitter..
so, thank you very much and
See you next time!